The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Today we're going to solve three problems,
教授：今天我们要解决三个问题，
a problem called Parenthesization,
一个叫做括号的问题，
a problem called Edit Distance, which is used in practice
在实践中会使用一个称为“编辑距离”的问题
a lot, for things like comparing two strings of DNA,
在很多方面，例如比较两串DNA，
and a problem called Knapsack, just
还有一个叫做背包的问题
about how to pack your bags.
关于如何打包行李。
And we're going to get a couple of general ideas,
我们将获得一些一般性想法，
one is about how to deal with string problems in general
一是关于如何处理字符串问题
with dynamic programming.
动态编程。
The first two and our previous lecture
前两个和我们之前的演讲
are all about strings, certain sense or sequences,
都是关于字符串，某种意义或序列的，
and we're going to introduce a new concept, kind
我们将介绍一种新的概念
of like polynomial time, but only kind of, sort of-- pseudo
像多项式时间，但只是一种
polynomial time.
多项式时间。
Remember, dynamic programming in five easy steps.
请记住，动态编程只需五个简单步骤。
You define what your sub problems are and count
您定义您的子问题并计算
how many there are, to solve a sub problem,
有多少解决一个子问题，
you guess some part of the solution, where there's not too
你猜想解决方案的某些部分
many different possibilities for that guess.
这种猜测有许多不同的可能性。
You count them, better be polynomial.
你算他们，最好是多项式。
Then you, using that guess-- this is sort of optional,
然后，您使用这种猜测-这是可选的，
but I think it's a useful way to think about things.
但我认为这是思考事情的有用方法。
You write a recurrence relating the solution to the subproblem
您编写与解决方案相关的子问题的重复记录
you want to solve, in terms of smaller subproblem, something
您想解决较小的子问题
that you already know how to solve,
您已经知道如何解决，
but it's got to be within this list.
但必须在此列表中。
And when you do that, you're going
当您这样做时，您将
to get a min or a max of a bunch of options,
获得一堆选项的最小值或最大值，
those correspond to your guesses.
这些符合您的猜测。
And you get some running time, in order
然后您会获得一些运行时间
to compute that recurrence, ignoring the recursion, that's
计算递归，而忽略递归，那就是
time for subproblem.
子问题的时间。
Then, to make a dynamic program, you either just
然后，要制作一个动态程序，您要么
make that a recursive algorithm and memoize everything,
使它成为递归算法并记住所有内容，
or you write the bottom up version of the DP.
或编写DP的自底向上版本。
They do exactly the same computations, more or less,
他们或多或少地进行完全相同的计算，
and you need to check that this recurrence is acyclic,
并且您需要检查这种复发是否为非周期性，
that you never end up depending on yourself,
你永远不会依赖自己
otherwise these will be infinite algorithms
否则这些将是无限算法
or incorrect algorithms.
或错误的算法。
Either way is bad.
两种方法都不好。
From the bottom up, you really like to explicitly know
从下至上，您真的很想明确地知道
a topological order on the subproblems,
子问题的拓扑顺序，
and that's usually pretty easy, but you've
通常很容易，但是您已经
got make sure that it's acyclic.
确保它是非循环的。
And then, to compute the running time of the algorithm,
然后，要计算算法的运行时间，
you just take the number of subproblems from part 1
您只需从第1部分中获取子问题的数量
and you multiply it by the time it takes
然后乘以所需的时间
per subproblem, ignoring recursion, in part 3.
每个子问题，忽略递归，在第3部分中。
That gives you your running time.
那给您您的运行时间。
I've written this formula by now three times
我已经写了三遍这个公式
are more, remember it.
还有，记住它。
We use it all the time.
我们一直在使用它。
And then you need to double check that you can actually
然后您需要仔细检查您是否可以
solve the original problem you cared about,
解决您关心的原始问题，
either it was one of your subproblems
要么这是你的子问题之一
or a combination of them.
或它们的组合。
So that's what we're going to do three times today.
这就是我们今天要做的三遍。
One of the hardest parts in dynamic programming
动态编程中最难的部分之一
is step 1, defining your subproblems.
是步骤1，定义子问题。
Usually if you do that right, it becomes-- with some practice,
通常，如果您做对了，通过实践，
step 2 is pretty easy.
第2步非常简单。
Step 1 is really where most of the insight comes in,
第1步确实是大多数洞察力产生的地方，
and step 3 is usually trivial, once you know 1 and 2.
一旦知道了1和2，步骤3通常就很简单了。
Once you realize 1 and 2 will work, the recurrence is clear.
一旦您意识到1和2将起作用，就很清楚了。
So I want to give you some general tips for step 1,
因此，我想向您介绍第1步的一些一般性提示
how to choose subproblems, and we're
如何选择子问题，我们
going to start with problems that involve strings
从涉及字符串的问题开始
or sequences as input, where the problem, the input
或序列作为输入，问题出在哪里
to the problem is string or sequence.
问题是字符串或序列。
Last class we saw text justification,
上一课，我们看到了文字对齐方式，
where the input was a sequence of words,
输入是一个单词序列，
and we saw Blackjack, where the input was a sequence of cards.
我们看到了二十一点，其中输入是一系列纸牌。
Both of these are examples, and if you look at them,
这两个都是示例，如果您查看它们，
in both cases we used suffixes, what
在两种情况下，我们都使用后缀，
do I call it, x, as our subproblems.
我称它为x是我们的子问题。
If x was our sequence, we did all the suffixes,
如果x是我们的序列，则我们完成所有后缀，
I equals zero up to the length of the thing.
直到事物的长度，我等于零。
So they're about n, n plus 1, such subproblems.
因此，它们大约是n，n加1的子问题。
This is good.
很好
Not very many of them, and usually if you're
他们不是很多，通常如果你是
plucking things off the beginning of the string
从字符串的开头删除内容
or of the sequence, then you'll be left with the suffix.
或序列号，那么您将获得后缀。
If you always are plucking from the beginning,
如果您总是从一开始就采摘，
you always have suffixes, you'll stay in this class,
您总是有后缀，您将继续上课，
and that's good, because you always
那很好，因为你总是
want a recurrence that relates, in terms
希望相关的复发
of the same subproblems that you know.
您知道的相同子问题。
Sometimes it doesn't work.
有时它不起作用。
Sometimes prefixes are more convenient.
有时前缀更方便。
These are usually pretty much identical,
这些通常是完全相同的
but if you're plucking off from the end instead
但是如果你从最后开始
of the beginning, you'll end up with prefixes, not suffixes.
首先，您将以前缀而不是后缀结尾。
Both of these have linear size, so they're
两者都具有线性尺寸，所以它们
good news, quite efficient.
好消息，效率很高。
Another possibility when that doesn't work,
当另一种方法不起作用时，
we're going to see an example of that today,
我们今天将看到一个例子
is you do all substrings.
是您处理所有子字符串吗？
So I don't mean subsequences, they
所以我不是说子序列
have to be consecutive substrains, i through j.
必须是从i到j的连续子应变。
And now for all i and j.
现在，对于所有我和j。
How many of these are there?
其中有几个？
For a string of length n?
对于长度为n的字符串？
N squared.
N平方。
So this one is n squared, the others are linear.
所以这个是n平方，其他是线性的。
Out of room here.
没房间了
Theta n.
塞塔
So you obviously you prefer to use these subproblems
因此，您显然希望使用这些子问题
because there's fewer of them, but if sometimes they
因为它们较少，但如果有时它们
don't work, then use this one, still polynomial, still
不起作用，然后使用这个仍然是多项式的
pretty good.
非常好。
This will get you through most DP's.
这将使您通过大多数DP。
It's pretty simple, but very useful.
这很简单，但非常有用。
Let me define the next problem we consider.
让我定义我们考虑的下一个问题。
For each of them we're going to go through the five steps.
对于他们每个人，我们将经历五个步骤。
So the first problem for today is parenthesization.
因此，今天的第一个问题是括号。
You're given an associative expression,
您会得到一个关联的表达，
and you want to evaluate it in some order.
您想按某种顺序进行评估。
So I'm going to-- for associative expression,
因此，我将要进行关联表达，
I'm going to think of matrix multiplication,
我要考虑矩阵乘法，
and I probably want to start at zero.
我可能想从零开始。
So let's say you have n matrices,
假设您有n个矩阵，
you want to compute their product.
您要计算其乘积。
So you remember matrix multiplication is not
所以你记得矩阵乘法不是
commutative, I can't reorder these things.
交换，我不能重新排序这些东西。
All I can do is, if I want to do it
我所能做的就是，如果我想做
by sequence of pairwise multiplications,
通过成对乘法的序列，
is I get to choose where the parentheses are, and do
我可以选择括号的位置，然后执行
whatever I want for the parentheses,
无论我想要什么括号，
because it's associative.
因为它是关联的。
It doesn't matter where they go.
他们去哪里都没关系。
Now it turns out if you use straightforward matrix
现在事实证明，如果您使用简单矩阵
multiplication, really any algorithm for matrix
乘法，实际上任何矩阵算法
multiplication, it matters how you parenthesize.
乘法，括号的大小很重要。
Some will be cheaper than others,
有些会比其他便宜
and we can use dynamic programming
我们可以使用动态编程
to find out which is best.
找出最好的。
So let me draw a simple example.
因此，让我举一个简单的例子。
Suppose I have a column vector times a row
假设我有列向量乘以行
vector times a column vector.
向量乘以列向量。
And there are two ways to compute this product.
有两种计算此乘积的方法。
One is like this, and the other is like this.
一个是这样，另一个是这样。
If I compute the product this way,
如果我这样计算产品，
it's every row times every column,
它是每一行乘以每一列，
and then every row times every column,
然后每一行乘以每一列，
and every row times every column.
每一行乘以每一列
This subresult is a square matrix, so if these are-- say
该子结果是一个方矩阵，所以如果这些是-
everything here is n, and this will be an n by n matrix.
这里的所有内容都是n，这将是一个n×n的矩阵。
Then we multiply it by a vector and this computation
然后我们将其乘以一个向量，然后进行此计算
has to take, if you do it well, it
必须采取，如果做得好，
will take theta n squared time, because I
将花费theta n平方的时间，因为我
need to compute n squared values here,
这里需要计算n个平方值，
and then it's n squared to do this final multiplication.
然后进行最后的乘法运算n个平方。
Versus if I do it this way, I take all the rows here,
与如果我采用这种方式，我将把所有行都放在这里，
multiply them on all the columns here, it's a single number,
将它们乘以此处的所有列，这是一个数字，
and then I multiply by this column.
然后我乘以此列。
This will take linear time.
这将花费线性时间。
So this is better parenthesization than this one.
因此，比起此括号更好。
Now, I don't even need to define in
现在，我什至不需要定义
general for an x by y matrix, times a y by z matrix,
一般用x乘y矩阵乘以a乘z矩阵，
you can think about the running time of that multiplication.
您可以考虑该乘法的运行时间。
Whatever the running time is, dynamic programming
无论运行时间如何，动态编程
can solve this problem, as long as it only
可以解决这个问题，只要
depends on the dimensions of the matrices
取决于矩阵的尺寸
that you're multiplying.
你正在繁殖。
So for this problem, there's going
所以对于这个问题，
to be the issue of which subproblems we use.
成为我们使用哪个子问题的问题。
Now we have a sequence of matrices
现在我们有了一系列矩阵
here, so we naturally think of these as subproblems,
在这里，所以我们自然将这些视为子问题，
but before we get to the subproblems, let me ask you,
但是在我们讨论这些子问题之前，让我问你，
what you think you should guess?
您认为应该怎么猜？
Let's just say from the outset, if I give you
一开始就说，如果我给你
this entire sequence, what feature
这整个序列，有什么特点
of the solution of the optimal solution
最优解的解
would you like to guess?
你想猜吗？
Can't know the whole solution, because there's exponentially
无法知道整个解决方案，因为
many ways to parenthesize.
括号的方法很多。
What's one piece of it that you'd
你会做的一件事情是什么
like to guess that will make progress?
想猜会有所进步吗？
Any idea?
任何想法？
It's not so easy.
这不是那么容易。
AUDIENCE: Well, wouldn't you need the last operation?
听众：嗯，您不需要最后一次手术吗？
PROFESSOR: What's the last operation
教授：最后一次手术是什么
we're going to do, exactly.
确切地说，我们将要做。
You might call it the outermost multiplication
您可能称其为最外层乘法
or the last multiplication.
或最后的乘法。
So that's going to look like we somehow multiply a 0 through ak
这样看起来就像我们以某种方式将0乘以ak
minus 1, and then we somehow multiply aK through an minus 1,
减1，然后以某种方式将k乘以减1，
and this is the last one.
这是最后一个。
So now we have two subproblems.
所以现在我们有两个子问题。
Somehow we want to multiply this, somehow-- I mean,
我们想以某种方式将其相乘，我是说，
there's got to be some last thing you do.
你要做的最后一件事。
I don't know what it is, so just guess it.
我不知道这是什么，所以就猜吧。
Try all possibilities for k, it's got to be one of them,
尝试所有可能的k，它必须是其中之一，
take the best.
尽力而为。
If somehow we know the optimal way to do a0 to k minus 1
如果以某种方式我们知道将a0减至k减1的最佳方法
and the optimal way to ak to an minus 1, then we're golden.
以及将ak减为负1的最佳方法，那么我们就是黄金。
Now, this looks like a prefix, this looks like a suffix.
现在，这看起来像一个前缀，这看起来像一个后缀。
So do you think we can just combine subproblems, suffixes
那么您认为我们可以将子问题，后缀组合吗
and prefixes?
和前缀？
How many people think yes?
有多少人认为是？
A few?
一些？
How many people think no, OK, why?
有多少人认为不可以，为什么？
AUDIENCE: So, for example if you split, if you were to split,
听众：例如，如果您拆分了，如果您拆分了，
like [INAUDIBLE]?
像[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
The very next thing we're going to do
我们要做的下一件事
is recurse on this subproblem, recurse on this subproblem.
是在此子问题上递归的，是在此子问题上递归的。
When we recurse here, we're going
当我们在这里递归时，我们要
to split it into a0 to ak prime minus 1, and ak prime minus 1,
将其分为a0到ak素减1，和ak素减1，
or ak prime to ak minus 1.
或ak素数到ak减1。
We're going to consider all possible partitions,
我们将考虑所有可能的分区，
and this thing, from ak prime to ak minus 1,
这个东西，从ak素数到ak减1，
is not a prefix or a suffix.
不是前缀或后缀。
What is it?
它是什么？
A substring.
子字符串。
There's only one thing left.
只剩下一件事了。
I claim these are usually enough, and in this case
我声称这些通常就足够了，在这种情况下
substrings will be enough.
子串就足够了。
But this is how you can figure out
但这是您可以找出的方法
that, ah, I'm not staying within the family prefixes,
那啊，我不留在家庭前缀中，
I'm not staying within the family suffixes.
我不在家庭后缀之内。
In general, you never use both of these together.
通常，您永远不会将两者同时使用。
If you're going to need both, you probably need substrings.
如果您同时需要两者，则可能需要子字符串。
So if just suffixes work, fine.
因此，只要后缀有效，就可以了。
If just prefixes work, fine, but otherwise
如果只是前缀有效，那么可以，否则
you're probably going to need substrings.
您可能需要子字符串。
That's just a rule of thumb, of course.
当然，这只是一个经验法则。
Cool.
凉。
So, part 1 subproblem is going to be the optimal evaluation
因此，第1部分子问题将是最佳评估
parenthesization of ai to aj minus 1.
ai到aj的括号内减1。
So that's part of the problem here.
这就是这里问题的一部分。
We want to do a0 to n minus 1.
我们想做a0到n减1。
So in general, let's just take some substring in here
所以总的来说，让我们在这里取一些子字符串
and say, well what's the best way to multiply that,
然后说，乘以它的最佳方法是什么，
and that's the sorts of subproblems
那是种子问题
we're getting if we use this guess.
如果我们使用这个猜测，我们就会知道。
And if you start with a substring and you do this,
如果您以子字符串开头并执行此操作，
you will still remain within a substring,
您仍将保留在子字符串中，
so actually I have to revise this slightly.
所以实际上我必须对此稍作修改。
Now we're going from ai-- to solve this subproblem, which
现在我们要从人工智能着手解决这个子问题
is what we need to do in the guessing step,
是我们在猜测步骤中需要做的，
we start from ai, we go to some guest place, ak minus 1,
我们从ai开始，我们去某个客人的地方，ak减去1，
then from ak up to aj minus 1.
然后从ak到aj减1。
This is the i colon j subproblem.
这是第i个冒号j子问题。
So we guess some point in the middle, some choice for k.
因此，我们猜测中间的某个点，k的某些选择。
The number of choices for k is-- number
k的选择数是-
of possible choices for this guess,
这种猜测的可能选择，
so we have to try all of them, is like order j minus i plus 1.
所以我们必须尝试所有这些，就像阶数j减去i加1一样。
I put order in case I'm off by 1 or something.
我下订单以防万一我不满意。
But in particular this is [INAUDIBLE].
但特别是[听不清]。
And that's all we'll need.
这就是我们所需要的。
So that's the guess.
这就是猜测。
Now we go to step 3, which is the recurrence.
现在我们转到第3步，即重复。
And this-- we're going to do this over and over again.
这-我们将一遍又一遍地做。
Hopefully by the end, it's really obvious
希望到最后，这确实很明显
how to do this recurrence.
如何进行这种复发。
Let me just fix my notation, we're going to use dp,
我来修正一下符号，我们将使用dp，
I believe.
我相信。
For whatever reason, in my notes I often write dp of ij.
无论出于什么原因，我经常在笔记中写ij的dp。
This is supposed to be the solution
这应该是解决方案
to the subproblem i colon j.
子问题我冒号j。
I want to write it recursively, in terms of smaller
我想递归地写它
subproblems, and I want to minimize the cost,
子问题，我想将成本降到最低，
so I'm going to write a min overall.
所以我要写一分钟的整体。
And for each choice of k, so there's going to be a for loop,
对于k的每个选择，都会有一个for循环，
I'm going to use Python notation here with iterators.
我将在这里使用带有迭代器的Python表示法。
So k is going to be in the range,
因此，k将在该范围内，
I think range ij is correct.
我认为范围ij是正确的。
I'm going to double check there's no off by 1's here.
我要仔细检查这里是否没有1。
Says i plus 1j.
说我加1j。
I think that's probably right.
我认为可能是正确的。
Once I choose where k is, where I'm
一旦我选择k在哪里，我在哪里
going to split my multiplication,
要分割我的乘法
I do the cost for i up to k, that's
我为我付出了不超过k的费用，这就是
the left multiplication, plus the cost for k up to j,
左乘法，再加上k到j的成本，
plus-- so those are the two recursive multiplications.
加-所以这是两个递归乘法
So then I also have to do this outermost one.
因此，我还必须做这最外层的一个。
So how much does that cost?
那要花多少钱？
Well, it's something, so cost of the product
好吧，这就是产品的成本
ai colon k times the product ak colon j.
ai冒号k乘以ak冒号j。
So I'm assuming I can compute this cost,
所以我假设我可以计算出这笔费用，
not even going to try to write down a general formula,
甚至不打算写下一个通用公式，
you could do it, it's not hard, it's like xyz.
您可以做到，这并不难，就像xyz。
For a standard matrix multiplication algorithm.
用于标准矩阵乘法算法。
But whatever algorithm you're using,
但是无论您使用哪种算法，
assuming you could figure out the dimensions of this matrix,
假设您可以找出此矩阵的尺寸，
it doesn't matter how it's computed,
无论如何计算，
the dimensions will always be the same.
尺寸将始终相同。
You compute the dimensions of this matrix that
您计算该矩阵的维数
will result from that product, it's
将由该产品产生，它是
always going to be the first dimension
永远是第一维度
here, with the last dimension there.
在这里，最后一个尺寸在那里。
And it's constant time, you know that.
而且这是恒定的时间，您知道的。
And then if you can figure out the cost of a multiplication
然后，如果您能算出乘法的成本
in constant time, just knowing the dimensions
在恒定的时间内，只知道尺寸
of these matrices, then you could plug this
这些矩阵，那么您可以插入
in to this dynamic program, and you
进入这个动态程序，您
will get the optimal solution.
将获得最佳解决方案。
This is magically considering all possible parenthesizations
神奇地考虑了所有可能的括号
of these matrices, but magically it does it in polynomial time.
这些矩阵，但是神奇的是它可以在多项式时间内完成。
Because the time for subproblem here--
因为这里出现子问题的时间是
We're spending constant time for each iteration
我们每次迭代都花固定的时间
of this for loop, because this is
这个for循环，因为这是
a constant time just computing the cost.
一个恒定的时间，只是计算成本。
These are free recursive calls, so it's
这些是免费的递归调用，因此
dominated by the length of the for loop, which we already
由for循环的长度决定，我们已经
said was order n, so it's order n time for subproblem,
说是n阶，所以子问题是n阶
ignoring recursions.
忽略递归。
And so when we put this together,
因此，当我们将它们放在一起时，
the total time is going to be the number
总时间将是数字
of some problems, which I did not write.
有些问题，我没有写。
The number of problems in step 1 is n squared,
步骤1中的问题数为n的平方，
that's what we said over here, for substrings.
这就是我们在这里所说的子字符串。
So running time is number of subproblems, which is n
因此，运行时间就是子问题的数量，即n
squared, times linear for each, and so it's order n cubed,
平方，每个时间都是线性的，所以它的阶数为n，
it's actually theta n cubed.
它实际上是立方体。
So polynomial time, much better than trying
多项式时间，比尝试好得多
all possible parenthesizations, they're about 4
所有可能的括号，大约是4
to the n parenthesizations, that's a lot.
到n个括号，就很多了。
Topological order here is a little more interesting,
这里的拓扑顺序更有趣
if you think about that.
如果您考虑一下。
I can tell you, for suffixes, topological order
我可以告诉您后缀的拓扑顺序
is almost always right to left.
几乎总是从右到左。
And for prefixes, it's almost always
对于前缀，几乎总是
left to right, for increasing i, decreasing i.
从左到右，用于增加i，减小i。
For substrings, what do you think it is?
对于子字符串，您认为它是什么？
Or for this situation in particular?
还是针对这种情况？
In what order should I evaluate these subproblems?
我应该以什么顺序评估这些子问题？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: This is the running time
教授：这是运行时间
to determine the best way to multiply-- that's right.
确定最好的繁殖方式-是的。
So yeah, it's worth checking, because we also
是的，值得检查，因为我们也
have to do the multiplication.
必须做乘法。
But if you imagine this n, the number
但是如果你想象这个n
of matrices you're multiplying is probably
您要相乘的矩阵可能
much smaller than their sizes.
比它们的尺寸小得多。
In that situation, this will be tiny,
在那种情况下，这会很小
whereas the time to actually do the multiplication, that's
而实际进行乘法的时间是
what's being computed by the DP, hopefully that's much larger,
DP正在计算什么，希望它会更大，
otherwise you're kind of wasting your time doing the DP.
否则您会浪费时间进行DP。
But hey, at least you could tell somebody
但是，嘿，至少你可以告诉别人
that you did it optimally.
您做到了最佳。
But it gets into a fun issue of cost
但这成为一个有趣的成本问题
of planning verses execution, but we're not really
计划执行诗句，但是我们不是真的
going to worry about that here.
在这里担心这一点。
So, in what order should I evaluate this recurrence,
因此，我应该按什么顺序评估这种复发，
in order to-- I want, when I'm evaluating DP of ij,
为了-当我评估ij的DP时，
I've already done DP of ik and DP of kj,
我已经做过ik的DP和kj的DP，
and this is what you need for bottom up execution.
这就是自下而上执行所需的内容。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Small to large.
听众：从小到大。
PROFESSOR: Small to large, exactly.
教授：确切地说，从小到大。
We want to do increasing substring size.
我们要增加子字符串的大小。
That's actually what we're always
这实际上就是我们一直在做的
doing for all of those subproblems over there.
为那里的所有这些子问题做。
When I say all suffixes, you go right to left.
当我说所有后缀时，您从右到左。
Well, that's because the rightmost suffix is nothing,
嗯，那是因为最右边的后缀什么都没有，
and then you build up a larger and larger strings, same thing
然后建立越来越大的弦，同样的事情
here.
这里。
Exercise, try to draw the DAG for this picture.
练习，尝试为此图片绘制DAG。
It's a little harder, but if you-- I
有点难，但是如果你-我
mean you could basically imagine-- I'll do it for you.
意味着您基本上可以想象-我会为您做到的。
Here is, let's say-- well, at the top
我们可以说-好吧，在顶部
there's everything, the longest substring, that
所有的东西，最长的子串，
would be from zero to n, that's everything.
从零到n，仅此而已。
Then you're going to have n different ways
然后，您将拥有n种不同的方式
to have substrings of, or actually just
拥有或实际上只是
two different ways, to have a slightly smaller substring.
两种不同的方式，使子字符串略小一些。
At the bottom you have a bunch of substrings,
在底部，您有一堆子字符串，
which are the length zero ones, and in between,
长度为零，介于两者之间
like in the middle here, you're going
就像在中间
to have a much larger number.
有更大的数字。
And all these edges are pointed up,
所有这些边缘都指向上
so you can compute all the length
这样就可以计算出所有长度
zero ones without any dependencies and then just
没有任何依赖性的零个，然后
increasing in length.
长度增加。
It's a little hard to see, but in each case-- Yeah,
很难看，但是在每种情况下-是的，
ah, interesting.
啊，有趣。
This is a little harder to formulate as a regular shortest
将其简化为常规最短点有点困难
paths problem, because if you look at one of these nodes,
路径问题，因为如果您查看这些节点之一，
it depends on two different values,
它取决于两个不同的值，
and you have to take the sum of both of them.
而您必须将两者加起来。
And then you also add the cost of that split.
然后，您还要添加该拆分的成本。
Cool.
凉。
So this is the subproblem DAG, you could draw it,
这是子问题DAG，您可以绘制它，
but this DP is not shortest paths in that DAG.
但是该DP不是该DAG中的最短路径。
So perhaps dynamic programming is not just shortest paths
所以也许动态编程不仅仅是最短的路径
in a DAG, that's a new realization for me
在DAG中，对我来说这是一个新认识
as of right now.
截至目前。
OK.
好。
Some other things I forgot to do-- I
我忘记做的其他事情-我
didn't specify the base case.
没有指定基本情况。
The base case for that recurrence
重复发生的基本情况
is when your string is of length 0 or even of length 1,
是当您的字符串的长度为0或什至长度为1时
because when it's length 1, there's only one matrix,
因为当它的长度为1时，只有一个矩阵
there's no multiplication to do, and so the cost is zero.
没有乘法可做，因此成本为零。
So you have something like dp of i, i plus 1 equals zero.
因此，您拥有i的dp之类的东西，我加1等于零。
That's the base case.
这是基本情况。
And then step 5, step 5 is what's
然后是步骤5，步骤5是什么
the overall problem I want to solve,
我要解决的整体问题
and that's just dp from 0 to n, that's the whole string.
那只是从0到n的dp，这就是整个字符串。
Any questions about that DP?
对那个DP有任何疑问吗？
I didn't write down, I didn't write down a memoized recursive
我没有写下来，也没有写下有记忆的递归
algorithm, you all know how to do that.
算法，你们都知道该怎么做。
Just do this for loop and put this inside,
只需将其放入循环并将其放入内部，
that would be the bottom up one, or just
那将是自下而上的一个，或者仅仅是
write this with memoization, that
带着回忆写下来
would be the recursive algorithm.
将是递归算法。
It's totally easy once you have this recurrence.
一旦复发，这是完全容易的。
All right, good.
好，好
How many people is this completely clear to?
这完全清楚了多少人？
OK.
好。
How many people does it kind of make sense?
这对多少人有意义？
And how many people it doesn't make sense at all?
还有多少人根本没有意义呢？
OK, good.
好好
Hopefully we're going to shift more
希望我们能做得更多
towards the first category.
对第一类。
It's a little magical, how this guessing works out,
这有点神奇，这种猜测如何实现，
but I think the only way to really get it is to see more
但我认为真正获得它的唯一方法是看到更多
examples and write code to do it,
示例并编写代码来做到这一点，
that's-- the ladder is your problem set,
那是-阶梯是您的问题所在，
examples is what we'll do here.
例子就是我们在这里要做的。
So next problem we're going to solve.
因此，我们要解决下一个问题。
Dynamic programming is one of these things that's
动态编程是其中的一件事
really easy once you get it, but it takes a little while
一旦获得它真的很容易，但是要花一点时间
to get there.
到那里。
So edit distance, we're going to make things a little harder.
因此，编辑距离，我们将使事情变得更困难。
Now we're going to be given two strings instead of just one.
现在，我们将获得两个字符串，而不仅仅是一个。
And I want to know the cheapest way to convert x into y.
而且我想知道将x转换为y的最便宜的方法。
I'm going to define what transform means.
我将定义转换的含义。
We're going to allow character edits.
我们将允许角色编辑。
We want to transform this string x into string y,
我们想将字符串x转换为字符串y，
so what character edits are we allowed?
那么我们允许哪些字符编辑？
Very simple, we're allowed to insert a character anywhere
很简单，我们可以在任意位置插入一个字符
in the strength, we're allowed to delete a character anywhere
从实力上讲，我们可以在任何地方删除角色
in the string, and we're allowed to replace a character anywhere
在字符串中，我们可以在任何地方替换字符
in the string, replace c with c prime.
在字符串中，将c替换为c prime。
Now, you could do a replacement by deleting c and inserting
现在，您可以通过删除c并插入来进行替换
c that's, one way to do it, but I'm
c那是做到这一点的一种方法，但是我
going to imagine that in general someone tells me
想像一般来说有人告诉我
how much each of these operations costs,
这些操作的成本是多少
and that cost may depend on the character you're inserting.
费用可能取决于您要插入的字符。
So deleting a character and then inserting a different character
所以先删除一个字符，然后再插入一个不同的字符
will cost one thing.
将花费一件事。
It will cost the sum of those two cost values.
它将花费这两个成本值的总和。
Replacing a character with another character
用另一个字符替换一个字符
might be cheaper.
可能更便宜。
It depends.
这取决于。
Someone gives me a little table, saying for this character,
有人给我一张桌子，说这个角色，
for letter a, it costs this much to insert, for letter
对于字母a，要花这么多钱
b it costs this much to insert, this much to delete,
b插入要花这么多钱，删除要花这么多钱，
and there's a little matrix for, if I
如果我有一个矩阵
want to convert an a into a b it costs this much to replace.
想要将a转换为ab，则替换成本很高。
Imagine, if you will, you're trying
想象一下，如果您愿意，您正在尝试
to do a spelling correction, someone's typing on a keyboard,
进行拼写更正，有人在键盘上打字，
and you have some model of, oh, well if I hit a,
你有一个模型，哦，好吧，如果我碰到一个，
I might have meant to hit an s, because s
我可能想打s，因为s
is right next to an a, and that's an easy mistake
就在a旁边，这是一个简单的错误
to make if you're not touch typing, because it's
如果您不触摸打字，那是因为
on the same finger, or maybe you're shifted over by one.
用同一根手指，或者也许您被移了一个。
So you can come up with some cost models,
因此，您可以提出一些成本模型，
someone could do a lot of work and research
某人可以做很多工作和研究
and whatnot and see what are typical typos,
然后看什么是典型的错别字，
replacing one letter for another,
用一个字母替换另一个字母，
and then associate some cost for each character,
然后为每个角色关联一些费用，
for each pair characters, what's the likelihood
对于每对字符，可能性是多少
that that was the mistake?
那是错误的吗？
I call that the cost, that's the unlikeliness.
我称这是成本，这不太可能。
And then you want to minimize the sum of costs,
然后，您希望将成本总和最小化，
and so you want to find what was the least set of errors that
所以您想找出最少的错误集
would end up with this word instead of this word.
最终将以这个词代替这个词。
You do that on all words of your dictionary
您对字典中的所有单词都执行此操作
and then you'll find the one that
然后您会找到一个
was most likely what you meant to type.
是您最想输入的内容。
And insertions and deletions are,
插入和删除是，
I didn't hit the key hard enough,
我没有足够努力地击键，
or I hit it twice, or accidentally hit a key
或我打了两次，或不小心打了一个键
because it was right next to another one, or whatever.
因为它紧挨着另一个，或者其他任何东西。
OK, so this is used for spelling correction.
好的，这用于拼写更正。
It's used for comparing DNA sequences,
它用于比较DNA序列，
and DNA sequences, if you have one strand of DNA,
和DNA序列，如果您有一链DNA，
there's a lot of mutation-- some mutations are
有很多突变-有些突变是
more likely than others.
比其他人更有可能。
For example, c to a g mutation is
例如，从c到ag的突变是
more common than c to an a mutation,
比c更常见于a突变，
and so you give this replacement a high cost,
因此您要付出高昂的代价，
you give this one a low cost, to represent
你给这低成本的代表
this is more likely than this.
比这更有可能。
And then at a distance will give your measure
然后距离一定可以给你量度
of how similar two DNA strings are evolutionarily.
两个DNA串在进化上有多相似。
And you also get extra characters randomly inserted
而且您还会随机插入额外的字符
and deleted in mutation.
并删除了突变。
So, it's a simplified model of what happens in mutation,
因此，它是突变发生情况的简化模型，
but still it's used a lot.
但仍然使用很多。
So all these are encompassed by edit distance.
因此，所有这些都包含在编辑距离中。
Another problem encompassed by edit distance
编辑距离包含的另一个问题
is the longest common subsequence problem.
是最长的常见子序列问题。
And I have a fun example, which I spent some hours,
我有一个有趣的例子，我花了几个小时，
way back when, coming up with.
回来的时候，想出了。
I can't spell it, though.
不过，我无法拼写。
It's such a weird word.
这是一个很奇怪的词。
Hieroglyphology is an English word
象形文字是一个英语单词
and Michelangelo is another English word,
而米开朗基罗是另一个英文单词，
if you allow proper nouns, unlike Scrabble.
如果您允许专有名词，则与Scrabble不同。
So, think of these as strings.
因此，将它们视为字符串。
This is x, this is y.
这是x，这是y。
What is the longest common subsequence?
最长的公共子序列是什么？
So not substring, I get to choose--
所以不是子字符串，我可以选择-
I can drop any set of letters from x, drop any set of letters
我可以从x中删除任何一组字母，也可以删除任何一组字母
from y, and I want them to, in the end, be equal.
从y开始，我希望它们最终相等。
It's a puzzle for you.
这对你来说是一个难题。
While you're thinking about it, you
在思考的时候，
can model this as an edit distance problem,
可以将其建模为编辑距离问题，
you just define the cost of an insert or a delete to be 1,
您只需将插入或删除的费用定义为1，
and the cost of a replace to be 0.
替换成本为0。
So this is a c to c prime replacement.
因此，这是交流的c素替换。
It's going to be 0 if c equals c prime,
如果c等于c素数，它将为0，
and I guess infinity otherwise.
我猜是无穷大。
You just don't consider it in that situation.
您只是不考虑这种情况。
Can anyone find the longest common subsequence here?
谁能在这里找到最长的公共子序列？
It's in English word, that's a hint.
用英语单词，这是一个提示。
So if you do this you're, basically
因此，如果您这样做，基本上
trying to minimize number of insertions and deletions.
试图减少插入和删除的次数。
Insertions in x correspond to deletions in y,
x中的插入对应于y中的删除，
and deletions in x correspond to deletions in x.
x中的删除对应于x中的删除。
So this is the minimum number of deletions in both strings,
所以这是两个字符串中最小的删除次数，
so you end up with a common substring.
因此，您最终得到一个通用的子字符串。
Because replacement says, I don't pay anything
因为更换说，我什么都不付
if the characters match exactly, otherwise I pay everything.
如果字符完全匹配，否则我将支付所有费用。
I'd never want to do this, so if there's a mismatch
我永远都不想这样做，所以如果不匹配
I have to delete it.
我必须删除它。
And so this model is the same thing
所以这个模型是同一回事
as long as common subsequence.
只要共同的子序列。
I want to solve this more general problem,
我想解决这个更普遍的问题，
it's actually easier to solve the more general problem,
解决更一般的问题实际上更容易，
but in particular, you can use it
但特别是您可以使用它
to solve this tricky problem.
解决这个棘手的问题。
Any answers?
有什么答案吗？
Yeah.
是的
Hello.
你好。
Very good.
很好。
Hello is the longest common subsequence.
你好是最长的普通子序列。
You can imagine how I found that.
您可以想象我是如何发现的。
Searching for all English words that
搜索所有的英语单词
have "hello" as the subsequence.
以“ hello”作为子序列。
That can also be done in polynomial time.
这也可以在多项式时间内完成。
So how are we going to do this?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
Well, I'd like to somehow use subproblems for strings,
好吧，我想以某种方式对字符串使用子问题，
suffixes, prefixes, or substrings.
后缀，前缀或子字符串。
But now I have two strings, that's kind of annoying.
但是现在我有两个字符串，这很烦人。
But don't worry, we can do sort of dynamic programming
但是不用担心，我们可以进行一些动态编程
simultaneously over x and y.
同时在x和y上。
What we're going to do is look at suffixes of x and suffixes
我们要做的是看x和后缀
of y, and to make our subproblems
y的子问题
we need to combine all of those subproblems by multiplication.
我们需要通过乘法来组合所有这些子问题。
We need to think about both of them simultaneously.
我们需要同时考虑两者。
So subproblem is going to be solve edit distance,
因此，子问题将是解决编辑距离问题，
edit distance problem on two different strings,
在两个不同的字符串上编辑距离问题，
a suffix of x and a possibly different suffix of y.
x的后缀和y的可能不同的后缀。
Because this is for all possible i and j choices.
因为这适用于所有可能的i和j选择。
And so the number of subproblems is?
那么子问题的数量是多少？
AUDIENCE: N squared.
听众：N平方。
PROFESSOR: N squared, yes.
教授：N平方，是的。
If x is of length n and y is of length n,
如果x的长度为n而y的长度为n，
there's n choices for this, n choices for that,
有n种选择，有n种选择，
and we have to do all of them as pairs,
我们必须将它们全部成对进行，
if there's n squared pairs.
如果有n个平方对。
In general, if they have different lengths,
通常，如果它们的长度不同，
it's going to be the length of x times length of y.
这将是x的长度乘以y的长度。
It's quadratic.
这是二次方。
Good.
好。
So, next we need to guess something, step 2.
因此，接下来我们需要猜测，步骤2。
This is maybe not so obvious, let's see.
让我们来看看这可能不是很明显。
You have here's x, starting at position i.
您的位置是x，从位置i开始。
You have y starting at position j.
您从位置j开始有y。
Somehow I need to convert x into y,
我不知何故需要将x转换为y，
I think it's probably better if I line these up,
我认为如果将它们排列起来可能会更好，
even though in some sense they're not lined up,
即使从某种意义上说他们没有排队，
that's OK.
没关系。
I want to convert x into y.
我想将x转换为y。
What should I look at here?
我应该在这里看什么？
Well, I should look at the very first characters,
好吧，我应该看看第一个字符，
because we're looking at suffixes.
因为我们正在查看后缀。
We want to cut off first characters somehow.
我们想以某种方式切断第一个字符。
How could it-- what are the possible ways to convert, or to
怎么可能-转换或转换成什么可能的方法
deal with the first character of x?
处理x的第一个字符？
What are the possible things I could do?
我可能会做些什么？
Given that, ultimately, I want the first character
鉴于此，最终，我想要第一个角色
of x to become the first character of y.
x成为y的第一个字符。
AUDIENCE: Delete [INAUDIBLE].
听众：删除[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: You could delete this character
教授：您可以删除此字符
and then insert this one, yes.
然后插入这个，是的。
Other things?
其他事情？
There's a few possibilities.
有几种可能性。
If you look at it right, there are three possibilities.
如果您看对了，就有三种可能。
And three possibilities are insert, delete, or replace.
三种可能性是插入，删除或替换。
So let's figure out how that's the case.
因此，让我们弄清楚情况如何。
I could replace this character with that character,
我可以用那个字符代替这个字符，
so that's one choice.
这是一种选择。
That will make progress.
那将会取得进展。
Once I do that, I can cross off those first characters
一旦这样做，我就可以删除第一个字符
and deal with the rest of the substrings.
并处理其余的子字符串。
Let's think about insert and delete.
让我们考虑一下插入和删除。
If I wanted to insert, presumably, I
如果我想插入，大概是
need this character at some point.
在某个时候需要这个角色。
So in order to make this character,
因此，为了使这个角色，
if it's not going to come from replacing this one,
如果不是要替换这一个，
it's got to be from inserting that character right there.
一定要从那里插入那个字符开始。
Once I do that, I can cross out that newly inserted character
一旦这样做，我就可以删掉新插入的字符
in this one, and then I have all of the string x from i
在这个中，然后我从i中获得了所有的字符串x
onward still, but then I've removed one character from y,
仍然向前，但是后来我从y中删除了一个字符，
so that's progress.
这样就可以了。
The other possibility is deletion,
另一种可能是删除
so maybe I delete this character,
所以也许我删除这个角色，
and then maybe I insert it in the next step,
然后也许我将其插入下一步
but it could be this character matches that one,
但可能是这个角色与那个角色匹配，
or maybe I have to delete several characters before I
也许我必须先删除几个字符
get to one that matches, something.
找到一个匹配的东西。
But I don't know that, so that's hard to guess,
但是我不知道，所以很难猜测，
because that would be more time to guess.
因为那将是更多的时间去猜测。
But I could say, well, this character might get deleted.
但是我可以说，这个字符可能会被删除。
If it gets deleted, that's it, it gets deleted.
如果它被删除，就是这样，它也会被删除。
And then somehow the rest of the x, from i plus 1 on,
然后以某种方式从我加1开始，剩下的x
has to match with all of y, from j on.
从j开始必须与所有y匹配。
But those are the three possibilities,
但这是三种可能性，
and in some sense capture all possibilities.
从某种意义上讲，抓住了所有可能性。
So it could be we replace xi with yj,
所以可能是我们用yj代替xi
and so that has some cost, which we're given.
因此，这需要一些费用，这是我们得到的。
It could be that we insert yj at the beginning,
可能是我们在开头插入了yj，
or it could be that we delete xi.
或者可能是我们删除了xi。
You can see that's definitely spanning
您可以看到这肯定跨越了
all the possible operations we can do,
我们可以做的所有可能的操作，
and if you think about it long enough,
如果你考虑了足够长的时间，
you will be convinced this really
您将确信这真的
covers every possible thing you can do.
涵盖了您可以做的所有可能的事情。
If you think about the optimal solution,
如果您考虑最佳解决方案，
it's got to do something to make this first character.
必须要做些什么才能使第一个角色成为现实。
Either it does it by replacement or it does it by an insertion.
它可以通过替换来实现，也可以通过插入来实现。
But if it inserts it later on, it's
但是如果以后再插入它，
got to get this out of the way somehow,
必须以某种方式解决这个问题，
and that's the deletion case.
这就是删除案例。
If it inserts it at the beginning, that's the insertion
如果它在开头插入，那就是插入
case, if it just does a replacement,
情况下，如果只是替换，
that's the replace case.
那是替换案例。
Those are all possibilities for the optimal solution.
这些都是最佳解决方案的可能性。
Then you can write a recurrence, which
然后，您可以编写一个循环
is just a max of those things, those three options.
只是这三个选项的最大值。
So I'm going to write, I guess, dp of ij, yes, of i,j,
我想写的是ij的dp，是的，i，j，
but now i,j is not a substring.
但是现在i，j不是子字符串。
It's a suffix of x and a suffix of y,
它是x的后缀和y的后缀，
so it corresponds to this subproblem.
因此它对应于此子问题。
If I want to solve that subproblem,
如果我想解决这个子问题，
it's going to be the min of three options.
这将是三个选项的最小值。
We've got the replace case, so it's
我们有替换盒，所以
going to be some cost of the replace, from xi to yj.
从xi到yj，将需要一些更换费用。
So that's a quantity which we're given.
这就是我们得到的数量。
Plus the cost of the rest.
加上其余的费用。
So after we do this replacement, we can cross off
因此，在执行此替换之后，我们可以取消
both those characters, and so we look at i plus 1 on
这两个字符，所以我们看我加1
for x, and j plus 1 onwards for y.
x表示，j表示y加1。
So that's option 1.
这就是选项1。
Then comma for the min.
然后用逗号隔开。
Option 2 is we have the cost of insert yj.
选项2是我们有插入yj的费用。
So that's also something we're given.
这就是我们得到的。
Then we add on what we have to do afterwards,
然后，我们添加之后要做的事情，
which is we've just gotten rid of yj,
这就是我们刚摆脱了yj，
so x still has the entire string from i on,
所以x仍然有从i开始的整个字符串，
and y has a smaller string.
y的字符串较小。
Comma.
逗号。
Last option is basically the same, cost of the delete,
最后一个选项基本相同，删除的费用，
deleting xi, and then we have to add on DP of i plus 1j.
删除xi，然后我们必须在i加上1j的DP上加上。
Because here we did not advance y but we advanced x.
因为在这里我们没有推进y但我们推进了x。
It's crucial that we always advance at least one
至关重要的是，我们必须至少提前一个
of the strings, because that means we're making progress,
的字符串，因为这意味着我们正在取得进步，
and indeed, if you want to jump to step 4, which is topological
实际上，如果您想跳到步骤4，这是拓扑
ordering-- sorry, I reused my symbols here,
订购-抱歉，我在这里重复使用了我的符号，
some different symbols.
一些不同的符号。
Head back to step 4 of DP, topological order.
返回到DP的第4步，拓扑顺序。
Well, these are suffixes, and so I
好，这些都是后缀，所以我
know with suffixes I like to go from the smaller
知道后缀，我喜欢从较小的后缀开始
suffixes, which is the end, to the beginning.
后缀，即结尾。
And, indeed, because we're always increasing,
而且，的确，因为我们一直在增长，
we're always looking at later substrings, later suffixes,
我们总是在查看后面的子字符串，后面的后缀，
for one or the other.
一个或另一个。
It's enough to just do-- come over here.
要做就足够了-过来这里。
To just do that for both of the strings,
为了对两个字符串都做到这一点，
it doesn't really matter the order.
顺序并不重要。
So you can do for i equals x down to zero,
所以你可以做，因为我等于x降到零，
for j equals y down to zero, and that will work.
因为j等于y减小到零，这将起作用。
Now this is another dynamic programming
现在这是另一个动态编程
you can think of as just shortest paths in the DAG.
您可以将其视为DAG中最短的路径。
The DAG is most easily seen as a two-dimensional matrix, where
DAG最容易被视为二维矩阵，其中
the i index is between zero and length of x, and the j index
i索引介于零和x的长度之间，而j索引
is between zero and length of y, and each
在零和y的长度之间，并且每个
of the cells in this matrix is a node in the DAG.
该矩阵中的单元格中的一个是DAG中的节点。
That's one of our subproblems, dp of ij.
那是我们的子问题之一，ij的dp。
And it depends on these three adjacent cells.
它取决于这三个相邻的单元格。
The edges are like this.
边缘是这样的。
If you look at it, we have to check i
如果您看的话，我们必须检查一下
plus 1, j plus 1, that's this guy.
加1，加1，就是这个人。
We have to check ij plus 1, that's this guy.
我们必须检查ij加1，就是这个家伙。
We have to check i plus 1j, that's this guy.
我们必须检查我加1j，就是这个家伙。
And so, as long as we compute the matrix this way,
因此，只要我们以此方式计算矩阵，
what I've done here is row by row, bottom up.
我在这里所做的是逐行，自下而上的。
You could do it anti-diagonals, you
你可以做反对角线，你
could do it column by column backwards, all of those
可以逐列地向后做，所有这些
will work because we're making progress towards the origin.
之所以会奏效，是因为我们正在朝着原点迈进。
And so if you ever-- if you look up at a distance,
因此，如果您-如果您抬头望远，
most descriptions think about it in the matrix form,
大多数描述都是以矩阵形式考虑的，
but I think it's easier to think of it in this recursive form,
但我认为以这种递归形式更容易想到它，
whatever your poison.
不管你的毒药
But this is, again, shortest paths in a DAG.
但这又是DAG中最短的路径。
The original problem we care about
我们关心的原始问题
is dp of zero zero, the upper left corner.
是dp零零，左上角。
So to be clear in the DAG, what you write here
因此，在DAG中要清楚一点，您在此处写的内容
is like the cost of, the weight of that edge
就像成本，那边缘的重量
is the cost of, I believe, a deletion.
我认为是删除的代价。
Deletion, oh sorry, it's an insertion.
删除，抱歉，这是一个插入。
Inserting that character, this one's a cost of deletion,
插入该字符，这是删除的代价，
this is a cost to replace, so you just put those edge weights
这是更换的成本，因此您只需放置这些边缘权重
in, and then just do a shortest paths in the DAG,
进入，然后在DAG中做最短的路径，
I think, from this corner to this corner.
我认为，从这个角落到这个角落。
And that will give you this, or you could just do this for loop
那会给你这个，或者你可以做这个for循环
and do that in the for loop, same thing.
然后在for循环中执行相同操作
OK.
好。
What's the running time?
几点钟了？
Well, the number of subproblems here is x times y,
嗯，这里的子问题数是y的x倍，
the running time for subproblem is?
子问题的运行时间是？
I'm assuming that I know these costs in constant time,
我假设我会不断了解这些费用，
so what's the overall running time of that, evaluating that?
那么，对其进行评估的总运行时间是多少？
Constant.
不变。
And so the overall running time is the number of subproblems
因此，总的运行时间就是子问题的数量
times a constant equals x times y.
常数乘以x乘以y。
This is the best known algorithm for edit distance,
这是最著名的编辑距离算法，
no one knows how to do any better.
没有人知道如何做得更好。
It's a big open problem whether you can.
是否可以这样做是一个很大的开放问题。
You can improve the space a little bit,
您可以稍微改善空间，
because we really only need to store
因为我们真的只需要存储
the last row or the last column, depending
最后一行或最后一列，具体取决于
on the order you're evaluating things.
根据您要评估的顺序。
To even get down to linear space, as far as we know,
据我们所知，甚至进入线性空间，
we need quadratic time.
我们需要二次时间。
One more problem, are you ready?
还有一个问题，您准备好了吗？
This one's going to blow your minds hopefully.
希望这会让您大吃一惊。
Because we're going to diverge from strings and sequences,
因为我们要从字符串和序列中分离出来，
kind of.
的种类。
So far everything we've looked at involves one or two
到目前为止，我们研究的所有内容都涉及一两个
strings or sequences, except for [INAUDIBLE].
字符串或序列，[音频不清晰]除外。
That involved a graph, that was a little more exciting.
这涉及到一个图表，这更令人兴奋。
But we'd already seen that, so it wasn't that exciting.
但是我们已经看到了，所以并不令人兴奋。
OK, our last problem for today is knapsack.
好，今天我们的最后一个问题是背包。
It's a practical problem.
这是一个实际的问题。
You're going camping.
你要去露营。
You're going backpacking, I should say,
你要去背包旅行，我应该说，
and you can only afford to take whatever
而且你只能负担任何
you can fit on your back.
你可以背对背。
You have some limit to capacity, let's say
假设您对容量有一定的限制
one giant backpack is all you can carry.
一个巨大的背包就可以随身携带。
Let's imagine it's the size of the backpack that matters,
假设重要的是背包的大小，
not the weight, but you could reformulate
不是重量，但您可以重新设定
this in terms of weight.
就重量而言。
And you've got a lot of stuff you want to bring.
而且您有很多要带的东西。
Ideally you bring everything you own,
理想情况下，您要拥有自己的一切，
that would be kind of nice, convenient,
那会很好，方便，
but it'd be kind of heavy.
但是有点沉重
So you're limited, you're not able to do that.
因此，您受到限制，无法执行此操作。
So you have a list of items and each of them has a size, si,
因此，您有一个项目列表，每个项目都有一个大小si，
and has a desire, a value to you,
对你有一种渴望，一种价值，
how much you care about it, how much you need it on this trip.
您有多在乎它，这次旅行中您需要多少。
OK, each item has two things, and the sizes are integers.
好的，每个项目都有两件事，并且大小是整数。
This is going to be important.
这将很重要。
It won't work without that assumption.
没有这个假设，它将无法正常工作。
And we have a knapsack, backpack,
我们有一个背包，背包，
whatever, I guess it's the British, but I don't know,
随便，我猜是英国人，但我不知道，
I get confused.
我有点迷惑不解了。
Growing up in Canada, I use both, so it's very confusing.
我在加拿大长大，我俩都使用，所以非常令人困惑。
Knapsack of total size, S.
总尺寸背包，S。
And what you'd like to do is choose a subset of the items.
而您想要做的就是选择项的子集。
If you're lucky, the sum of the si's fit within s,
如果您很幸运，则si在s内的总和，
then you bring everything.
然后你带来一切。
But if you're not lucky, that's not possible,
但是，如果您不走运，那是不可能的，
you want to choose a subset of the items whose total size is
您要选择总大小为
less than or equal to s, in order
小于或等于s
to maximize the sum of the values.
最大化值的总和。
So you want to maximize the sum of values
所以你想最大化价值的总和
for a subset of items, of total size less than or equal to S.
对于总大小小于或等于S的项目子集。
You can imagine size as weights instead of size, not
您可以将尺寸想象为重量而不是尺寸，而不是
a big deal, or you could have sizes and weights.
很大，否则您可能会有尺寸和重量。
All of these things generalize.
所有这些事情都是普遍的。
But we're going to need that the sizes/weights are integers.
但是我们将需要大小/权重为整数。
And so the items have to fit, because you can't cheat,
所以这些物品必须适合，因为你不能作弊，
you can't have more things than what fit,
你所拥有的东西不能超过适合的东西，
but then you want to maximize the value.
但是您想最大化价值。
How do we do this with dynamic programming?
我们如何通过动态编程做到这一点？
With difficulty.
有困难。
I don't have a ton of time, so I think
我没有很多时间，所以我认为
I'm going to tell you-- well, let's see.
我要告诉你-好吧，让我们看看。
Start with guessing.
从猜测开始。
This is the easy part to this problem.
这是解决此问题的容易部分。
We should also be thinking about subproblems at the same time.
我们还应该同时考虑子问题。
Even though I said we're leaving sequences, in fact,
即使我说过我们要离开序列，实际上，
we have a sequence here, we have a sequence of items.
我们这里有一个序列，我们有一个项目序列。
We don't actually care about the order of the items, but hey,
我们实际上并不关心项目的顺序，但是，
they're in an order.
他们有秩序。
If they weren't, we could put them in an order,
如果不是，我们可以将它们整理好，
in an arbitrary order.
以任意顺序。
We're going to use that order, and we're
我们将使用该顺序，并且
going to look at suffixes of items.
要查看项目的后缀。
i colon of items.
我冒号的项目。
That's helpful, because now it says, oh, well, we
这很有用，因为现在它说，哦，嗯，我们
should be plucking off items from the beginning.
应该从一开始就摘掉物品。
Starting with the i-th item, what
从第i个项目开始，
should I decide about the i-th item,
我应该决定第i个项目
relative to the optimal solution?
相对于最佳解决方案？
What should I guess?
我应该怎么猜？
AUDIENCE: Is i included or not?
听众：我是否包括在内？
PROFESSOR: Is i included or not, exactly.
教授：我是否被包括在内。
Is item i in the subset or not.
项目i是否在子集中。
Two choices, easy.
两种选择，简单。
Of course, those are the choices.
当然，这些是选择。
If I do that for everybody, then I know the entire subset.
如果我为所有人做到这一点，那么我将了解整个子集。
Somehow I need to be able to write
我需要以某种方式能够写
and this is what's actually impossible
这实际上是不可能的
if I choose this as my subproblem.
如果我选择这个作为我的子问题。
I want to write DP of i, somehow, in terms of, I guess,
我想以某种方式写i的DP，我想，
DP of i plus 1.
我加1。
And we'd like to do max, and either we don't put it in,
而且我们想做到最大，或者我们不把它放进去，
in which case that's our value, or we put it in, in which case
在这种情况下，这就是我们的价值，或者在这种情况下，我们将其投入其中
we get an additional v i in value.
我们将获得额外的vi价值。
OK, but we consume in size, and there's
可以，但是我们会消耗很多，
no way to remember that we've consumed the size here.
没有办法记住我们已经在这里消耗了大小。
We just called DP of i plus 1.
我们只称i + 1的DP。
In this case, it has everything, all this.
在这种情况下，它拥有一切。
In this case, we lose si of S, but we
在这种情况下，我们失去S的si，但是我们
can't represent that here.
在这里不能代表这一点。
That's bad, this would be an incorrect algorithm.
不好，这将是错误的算法。
I would always choose to put everything in,
我总是会选择放所有东西，
because it's not keeping track of the size bound.
因为它没有跟踪大小限制。
There's no capital S in this formula, that's wrong.
该公式中没有大写字母S，这是错误的。
So, to fix that, I'm going to write that again,
因此，要解决此问题，我将再次编写，
but a subproblem is going to have more information,
但是一个子问题将需要更多信息，
it's going to have an index i, and it's
它会有一个索引i，它是
going to have remaining capacity.
将具有剩余容量。
I'm going to call it capital X, at some integer at most
我将其称为大写X，最多为一个整数
S. We're assuming that the sizes are all integers,
S.我们假设大小都是整数，
so this is valid.
所以这是有效的。
The number of subproblems is equal to n,
子问题的数量等于n，
the number of items, did I say there are n items?
项目数，我说有n个项目吗？
Now there are n items, times capital S, really S plus 1,
现在有n个项目，乘以资本S，实际上是S加1，
because I have to go down to zero.
因为我必须降至零。
But n times S, different subproblems.
但是n乘以S，则存在不同的子问题。
Now for each of them I can write a recurrence,
现在我可以为每个人写一个循环
and that is DP of i comma s, is going
那就是我逗号的DP，
to be the max of DP of i plus 1s.
是i加上1的DP的最大值。
This is the case where we don't include the items,
在这种情况下，我们不包含商品，
so S stays the same.
所以S保持不变。
Actually I should write x here, because it's not actually
其实我应该在这里写x，因为实际上不是
our original value of s.
s的原始值。
x is the general situation.
x是一般情况。
The other possibility is we include item i,
另一种可能性是我们包括项目i，
and then we give DP of i plus 1.
然后给定DP的i加1。
We still consume item i.
我们仍然消耗物品i。
We now have x minus si as our new capacity,
现在，我们将x减si作为我们的新容量，
what remains after we add in this item.
添加此项目后剩下的内容。
And then we add on vi, because that's
然后我们添加vi，因为那是
the value we gain from putting that item in.
我们从放置该物品中获得的价值。
That's it, that's the DP, pretty simple.
就是这样，这就是DP，非常简单。
Let me say a little bit about the running time of this thing.
让我说说这件事的运行时间。
Again, you check there's a topological order and all
同样，您检查是否存在拓扑顺序，并且所有
that, it's in the notes.
那是在笔记中。
The total running time, we spend constant time
总的运行时间，我们花费恒定的时间
to evaluate this formula, so it's super easy.
评估此公式，因此超级简单。
The number of subproblems is the bottleneck.
子问题的数量是瓶颈。
So it's n times s.
所以是n倍。
Is this polynomial time?
这是多项式时间吗？
You might guess from the outline of today that the answer is no.
您可能从今天的轮廓中猜测答案是否定的。
This is not polynomial time.
这不是多项式时间。
What this polynomial time mean?
这个多项式时间是什么意思？
It's polynomial and n, where n is the size of the input.
它是多项式和n，其中n是输入的大小。
What's the size of the input here?
这里的输入大小是多少？
Well, we're given n items, each with a size, each with a value.
好吧，我们得到了n个项目，每个项目都有一个大小，每个都有一个值。
If you think of the sizes and values
如果您考虑规模和价值
as being single word items, then the size is n.
作为单个词项，则大小为n。
If you think of them as being ginormous values,
如果您认为它们是巨大的价值，
at most, the size of this input is
最多，此输入的大小为
going to be something like n times log s,
大约是n倍log s，
because if you write it out in binary
因为如果用二进制写出来
you would need log s, bits to write down those numbers.
您将需要log s位来写下这些数字。
But it is not n times s.
但这不是n倍。
This would be the binary encoding of the input,
这将是输入的二进制编码，
but the running time is this.
但是运行时间是这个
Now s is exponential in log s, this is, at best,
现在s在log s中是指数，这充其量是，
an exponential time algorithm.
指数时间算法。
But it's really not that bad if s is small,
但是，如果s很小，那真的不是那么糟糕，
and so we call it pseudopolynomial time.
所以我们称其为伪多项式时间。
What does pseudopolynomial mean?
伪多项式是什么意思？
It just means that your polynomial
就是说你的多项式
in n, the input size, which might be this,
在n中，输入大小（可能是这个）
and in the numbers that are in your input.
以及您输入的数字。
Numbers here means integers, basically,
基本上，这里的数字表示整数
otherwise it's not really well defined.
否则，它的定义不是很明确。
So in this case we have a bunch of integers,
因此，在这种情况下，我们有一堆整数，
but in particular we have s.
但特别是我们有。
And so there's S and the si's.
因此，有S和si。
This is definitely polynomial in n and s.
这绝对是n和s的多项式。
It is the product of n and S. So you
它是n和S的乘积。
think of this as pseudoquadratic time, I guess?
我认为这是伪二次时间吗？
Because it's quadratic, but one of the things is pseudo,
因为它是二次方，但是其中之一是伪的，
meaning it is one of the numbers in the input.
表示它是输入中的数字之一。
So if the number is big in k bits,
因此，如果数字以k位为大，
so I can write down a number that's of size 2 to the k.
所以我可以写下一个大小为k的2的数字。
So it's kind of in between polynomial and exponential,
所以它介于多项式和指数之间
you might say.
你可能会说。
Polynomial good, exponential bad,
多项式好，指数坏
pseudopolynomial, it's all right.
伪多项式，没关系。
That's the lesson.
这就是教训。
And for knapsack, this is the best we can do,
对于背包来说，这是我们所能做的最好的事情，
as we'll talk about later.
稍后再讨论。
Pseudopolynomial is really the best you could hope for.
伪多项式确实是您所希望的最好的。
So, sometimes that's as good as you can do
所以，有时候这就是你所能做的
and dynamic programming lets you do it.
动态编程使您可以做到这一点。